Finding Aid for Integrated Premedical-Medical Program (University of Michigan) publications, 1975-2003
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Integrated Premedical-Medical Program (University of Michigan) publications 1975-2003
University of Michigan. Integrated Premedical-Medical Program.
0.5 linear feet
9769 Bimu 2
Includes brochures, bulletins describing the program and courses offered, directories, manuals, and newsletters such as Inteflex News, the Inteflex Newsletter, and Inflexions. Also contains alumni newsletters such as the Inteflex Alumni News and Reflexions
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Publications are received periodically from the Integrated Premedical-Medical Program (donor # 8377 ).
Periodic additions to the records expected.
The collection is open without restriction.
Please consult the history found in the Integrated Premedical-Medical Program records finding aid.
The Integrated Premedical-Medical Program Publications (1 linear foot) are divided into two series: Unit Publications and Student Publications.
The Unit Publications series (.9 linear foot) includes brochures, bulletins describing the program and the courses offered, directories, manuals, and newsletters.
The directories are alphabetical lists of student telephone numbers and addresses for the classes of 1995, 1998, 1999, and 2002 published in 1994-1995. There is a similar directory for the class of 2004 published in 1996-1997. There is also a master address list for alumni compiled in 1996.
Inteflex issued its student manual from 1975 to 1997. The title changed several times. Published under the title Student's Guide to Survival in the Inteflex Program from 1975 to 1980 the title was modified to the Student's Guide to the Inteflex Program in 1981. From 1982 through 1984 it was called The Inteflex Student Handbook. In 1985 the title reverted to the Student's Guide to Survival in the Inteflex Program. The manuals are arranged alphabetically by title.
The Bentley Library holds Inteflex newsletters dating from 1974 to the present. These are arranged alphabetically by title. The Flex99 was a newsletter edited by and for members of the Inteflex Class of 1999. The Bentley Historical Library holds three issues from 1993 to 1994. The I-Opener was the newsletter written for students to describe their preceptorship experiences. We have issues from 1988 to 1996.
Alumni newsletters cover the years from 1982 to 2002. The Inteflex Alumni News was published from 1982 through 1983. In 1984 it became Reflexions: The Inteflex Alumni Newsletter. The Bentley Library has a nearly complete run of this publication except for volume 5 from 1986 and the issues for 2001.
The unit newsletter was titled Inteflex News in 1974 and continued to be published until 1995. There is one issue of Inteflex Program Newsletter dated 1976. The Inteflex Newsletter was issued from 1977 to 1979. In 1994 yet another newsletter entitled Inflexions was published. This newsletter ceased publication in 2002.
In 1972 the Inteflex External Advisory Committee met to assess the Inteflex program. The report compiled for that meeting gives a brief history, the objectives and design elements of Inteflex, committee structure and membership, and a description of the curriculum and courses offered. In addition under the heading "Website" there is a printout of the Inteflex website dating from 1997.
The Student Publications series (.1 linear foot) includes three anthologies by the students of Inteflex dating from 1995 through 1997. Each was published by the first year Inteflex class.
Subjects:
University of Michigan. Integrated Premedical-Medical Program.; Inteflex news.; Inteflex newsletter.; Inflexions.; Inteflex alumni news.; Reflexions.
Genre Terms:
Pamphlets.; Bulletins.; Directories.; Manuals.; Newsletters.
- Unit Publications
  - Brochures
    - Integrated Premedical-Medical Program, 1975-1997, undated (Box 1)
  - Bulletins
    - Integrated Premedical-Medical Program, 1973, undated (Box 1)
  - Directories
    - Inteflex Alumni Master Address List, 1996 (Box 1)
    - Inteflex Class of 1999 1998 and 1995, 1994-1995 (Box 1)
    - Inteflex Class of 2002 Current Addresses/Phone Numbers, 1994-1995 (Box 1)
    - Inteflex Class of 2004 Current Addresses/Phone Numbers, 1996-1997 (Box 1)
  - Invitations 1993-1997 (Box 1)
  - Manuals
    - Inteflex Guide
      - 1982 (Box 1)
    - The Inteflex Student Handbook
      - 1982-1984 (Box 1)
      - 1998-1999 (Box 1)
    - Student's Guide to Survival in the Inteflex Program
      - 1975, 1977, 1979-1980 (Box 1)
      - 1985-1990, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Student's Guide to the Inteflex Program
      - 1981 (Box 1)
      - 1991-1997, 6 folders (Box 1)
  - Newsletters
    - Flex99, 1993-1994 (Box 1)
    - The I-Opener, 1988-1996 vol. 2-9 (Box 1)
    - The I-Opener Preceptorship Newsletter, 1997-1999 (Box 1)
    - Inteflex Alumni News
      - 1982-1983 vol. 1-2, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Inteflex Counseling News, 1978 (Box 1)
    - Inteflex News
      - 1974-1995, 22 folders (Box 1)
    - Inteflex Newsletter, 1977-1979, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Inteflex Preceptorship News, 1987 (Box 1)
    - Inteflex Program Newsletter, 1976 (Box 1)
    - Inflexions, 1994-2002, 8 folders (Box 1)
    - Reflexions: The Inteflex Alumni Newsletter
      - 1984-1985 vol. 3-4, 2 folders (Box 1)
      - 1987-2000 vol. 6-18, 14 folders (Box 1)
      - 2002 (Box 1)
  - Reports
    - External Advisory Committee Meeting, 1972 (Box 1)
  - Web Pages
    - 1997 (Box 1)
- Student Publications
  - Anthologies
    - I, 1995 (Box 1)
    - Inside Out: An Anthology, 1996 (Box 1)
    - Inteflex Anthology 2003 (Box 1)
    - Signatures: Collected Works of the Inteflex Class of 2004 [1997] (Box 1)